<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<articles>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.10</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-07">2015-04-07</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			A small fix for some clients who aren't smart enough to resend HTTP OPTIONS after receiving a code 403 for the same.
			Fitted the XML (CalDAV, DAV, etc.) parser with proper namespace support via the <a
				href="http://expat.sourceforge.net/">libexpat</a> namespace handlers.
			Parsed documents are now properly checked for namespace and name of matching elements (e.g., <code>DAV::href</code>), not just
			the name itself.
			Run the XML parsing routines through <a href="http://lcamtuf.coredump.cx/afl/">AFL</a> for quite some time to shake out
			stray bugs.
			Add the ability to detect <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5545">iCalendar</a> components (<code>VCALENDAR</code>,
			<code>VEVENT</code>, <code>VTODO</code>, etc.) and properties (<code>UID</code>, <code>DTSTART</code>, etc.) during parse and
			stash references to them in linked component lists.
			This paves the way for filtering capabilities in later versions.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.11</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-10">2015-04-10</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Migrate the <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2617">RFC 2617</a> handling directly into <a
				href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi</a>, making the parse sequence just a little safer.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.12</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-12">2015-04-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Implement a nonce database to prevent replay attacks for digest authentication.
			This follows <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2617">RFC 2617</a> in maintaining a (bounded) database of nonce values and
			their counts.
			On first authentication, a new nonce field is created for the principal (possibly evicting the oldest nonce).
			Subsequent authentication must use this nonce as well as an increasing nonce-count.
			The methods are described in <a href="kcaldav.8.html">kcaldav(8)</a>.
			Also, have the gecos field in <a href="kcaldav.passwd.5">kcaldav.passwd(5)</a> contain the user's email address, then remove the
			email address field from <a href="kcaldav.conf.5">kcaldav.conf(5)</a>.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.13</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-13">2015-04-13</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			When accessing the server from a web browser (i.e., for HTML content), respond by printing the logged-in user's information and
			allow for changing of passwords or e-mail if the principal database has the correct permissions.
			This allows new users to perform simple administrative tasks without needing to log into the underlying UNIX server.
			See <a href="kcaldav.8.html">kcaldav(8)</a> for details.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.14</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-14">2015-04-14</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Add a flag to <a href="kcaldav.passwd.1.html">kcaldav.passwd(1)</a> to create new principal's home directories and populate them
			with a simple <a href="kcaldav.conf.5.html">kcaldav.conf(5)</a> file.
			Completely re-write the internal iCalendar parser to get ready for handling iCalendar dates.
			Add a handler for the default time-zone, encouraging GMT use, and minimum accepted date (epoch).
			Lastly, document each property we support (in the source) with a pointer to the RFC section.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.15</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-25">2015-04-25</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Allow web-based viewing of collection data.
			This works because GET isn't defined in calendar collections (according to <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4918">RFC
				4918</a>, section 9.4), so we can send all GET requests for collections to an HTML dynamic handler.
			Add initial <code>PROPPATCH</code> bits so that clients can (conditionally) set certain properties, e.g., iCal setting the
			calendar display name and colour.
			Add a framework for field-specific validation in the CalDAV parser to do so.
		</aside>
	</article>

	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.16</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-27">2015-04-27</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Support the <code>calendar-description</code> element.
			Consolidate all properties into a single structure, allowing for flexible addition and removal of properties and property
			behaviour.
			This also removes a lot of conditional logic when responding to <code>PROPFIND</code> and <code>REPORT</code> methods.
			The <code>DELETE</code> method has been cleaned up.
			All HTTP methods are now described in <a href="kcaldav.8.html">kcaldav(8)</a>, including available properties.
			Lots of internal support has been added for iCalendar <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2445#section-4.3.10">recurrence
				rule</a> computation, which is the major stepping stone for processing iCalendar dates, but this is not hooked into
			active use (yet).
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-03-23">2015-03-23</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Initial public release.
			This features only direct iCalendar access, tested on <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/projects/calendar/">Mozilla
				Lightning</a>.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-02">2015-04-02</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Simple CalDAV access using Lightning and Mac OS X 10.7 (<q>Lion</q>) iCal.
			The usual PUT, GET, and DELETE methods are supported, and a minimal (but functional) subset of PROPFIND and REPORT properties.
			See the <a href="kcaldav.8.html">kcaldav(8)</a> manual for details.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-03">2015-04-03</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Use the <a href="http://lcamtuf.coredump.cx/afl/">American fuzzy lop</a> to ferret out crashes and hangs in the <a
				href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5545">iCalendar</a> parser.
			Also move this parser to internally use a non-nil terminated buffer; thus, there's no additional copy necessary to a
			nil-terminated buffer.
			Support the <code>&lt;calendar-query&gt;</code> object for when the iPhone4 retrieves resources.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.7</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-04">2015-04-04</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Linux support thanks to a lot of compatibility glue.
			I'm especially displeased with Linux while doing this project: it doesn't even have <code>O_EXLOCK</code> and <code>O_SHLOCK</code>!
			I'm just using <a href="http://libbsd.freedesktop.org/wiki/">libbsd</a> to prevent code duplication.
			While refactoring, consolidate logging functions and add <a href="kcaldav.passwd.1.html">kcaldav.passwd(1)</a>.
			Run the principal parsing routines through the <a href="http://lcamtuf.coredump.cx/afl/">American fuzzy lop</a> (nothing found).
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.8</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-05">2015-04-05</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Verify that all <code>open()</code> invocations use advisory locks.
			Simplify re-opening locked files with <code>fdopen()</code> into its own utility function.
			Disallow symbolic links everywhere.
			(This may be relaxed in the future...)
			Drop privileges in <a href="kcaldav.passwd.1.html">kcaldav.passwd(1)</a>, making it sensitive to the <var>setuid</var> or
			<var>setgid</var> bits.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.0.9</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-06">2015-04-06</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Fully implement <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2617">RFC 2617</a> for authorisation.
			This includes the <q>MD5-sess</q>, <q>auth</q>, and <q>auth-int</q> directives.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.0</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-05-02">2015-05-02</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Migrate to using <a href="https://www.sqlite.org">SQLite</a> to store everything: nonces, collections, resources, configuration,
				and so on.
				This completely replaces the existing file-system based infrastructure, which was too brittle, with a single database file.
				All existing functionality is preserved, but there are some changes to be aware of if you're already using <span class="nm">kcaldav</span>.
				Foremost, you can now have multiple calendars.
				To effect this change, all user calendars are now within subdirectories of the calendar root, e.g.,
				<code>/cgi-bin/kcaldav/kristaps/calendar/</code> instead of directly in <code>.../kristaps/</code>.
				iOS and iCal clients deal with this properly, but Thunderbird will need to point directly to the calendar collection.
				Use the on-line interface or <a href="kcaldav.passwd.1.html">kcaldav.passwd(1)</a> to add calendars and calendar files.
			</div>
			<div>
				To migrate an existing installation, you'll need to create a new database file with <a href="kcaldav.passwd.1.html">kcaldav.passwd(1)</a>.
				Make sure that it's read-writable by the web server process.
				You'll then need to add your iCalendar files using the same tool.
				To migrate this server, I simply re-created my principal, then added the calendar files.
				In brief,
			</div>
			<pre>% cd /var/www/caldav
% kcaldav.passwd -f . -C
% kcaldav.passwd -f . -n `find kristaps -name \*.ics`</pre>
			<div>
				The unabridged form consists of using <code>sudo</code> and <code>-u kristaps</code>.
				For testing, note that the <span class="file">kcaldav.db</span> file can live alongside an existing installation.  
				So if you want to make sure it works, both can run alongside each other.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-05-12">2015-05-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Split out the CalDAV and iCalendar parsing routines into their own library, which is installed but not yet properly documented.
			The documentation will be fleshed out as <a href="libkcaldav.3.html">libkcaldav(3)</a>.
			Also re-renamed the Makefile rule <q>updatecgi</q> back into <q>installcgi</q>.
			This doesn't feature any updates to system functionality.
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-12-28">2015-12-28</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			Properly URL-encode and decode calendar entities.
			This arises when some calendar systems (e.g., Google) use non-alphanumerics in their Calendar names.
			Also relax an overly-strict rule when parsing the recursive rules as found by Reyk Floeter.  
			(Right now, the system doesn't use the recursive rule, so it's safe to have insane dates.)
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-12-28">2015-12-28</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				<strong>Warning</strong>: you'll need to dump your
				database and regenerate it with the included schema
				file <span class="file">kcaldav.sql</span>.
				New columns and constraints have been added to support delegation as described below.
			</div>
			<div>
				Added proxy functionality (see <a
					href="http://svn.calendarserver.org/repository/calendarserver/CalendarServer/trunk/doc/Extensions/caldav-proxy.txt">caldav-proxy.txt</a>).
				This has been tested with Apple's iCal, but not with other systems.  
				Delegation can be set from the client or from the web interface.
			</div>
			<div>
				Make web-interface access to the <q>null</q> directory (e.g., /cgi-bin/kcaldav) automatically redirect to the root directory
				instead of crashing the system.
				Moreover, allow <q>probe</q> requests (<code>PROPFIND</code> on the script root) properly redirect to the authenticated principal.
				While there, move the entire web interface to use JSON and JavaScript instead of dynamic HTML.
				This makes it easier to extend or replace.
			</div>
			<div>
				Updated the underlying database routines to better handle failure conditions and added more documentation to the code
				and explanations of error conditions.
				Sandbox the entire running process with <a
					href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man3/sandbox_init.3.html">sandbox_init(3)</a>
				(only applicable on Mac OS X).
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-03-02">2016-03-02</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				This small version allows integration with new <a href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi(3)</a> 0.7.5 facilities for
				debugging.
				This makes it easier to debug new CalDAV clients: see the <span class="file">Makefile</span> pre-processor options to
				enable debugging.
				If you have issues with a client, please enable full debugging and send me the exchange between the client and server.
				I've removed the options parsed by <a href="kcaldav.8.html">kcaldav(8)</a>, instead relying on compile-time options as
				defined (and documented) in the <span class="file">Makefile</span>.
				Fix some small nits found with <a href="http://clang-analyzer.llvm.org/scan-build.html">scan-build</a>.
				Add to <a href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcaldav">GitHub</a> and check with
				<a href="https://scan.coverity.com/projects/kcaldav">Coverity</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-07-05">2016-07-05</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Don't break multi-byte (UTF-8) streams.
				For the time being, this assumes that we're going to be encoded with UTF-8
				Also migrate to a <span class="file">GNUmakefile</span> instead of a <span class="file">Makefile</span>, which
				allows easier portability between systems.  Use a LOGFILE directive instead of logging to stderr.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2018-03-23">2018-03-23</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				First release in a long time!
				This brings us up to date with <a href="https://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi(3)</a> along with some simplifications.
			</div>
			<div>
				First, kick out the <span class="file">GNUmakefile</span> in favour of a simple <span class="file">Makefile</span>.
				Then, bring in <a href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/oconfigure">oconfigure</a> for compatibility.
				Lastly, relegate per-system changes to a <span class="file">Makefile.local</span>, making it easier for maintainers.
			</div>
			<div>
				Lastly, start using <a href="https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2">pledge(2)</a>
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.7</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2018-06-18">2018-06-18</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Merge fixes from <a href="https://github.com/mk-f">mk-f@</a> to
				handle <code>application/xml</code>, which requires the newest
				version of <a href="https://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi</a>.
				He was also awesome in fixing another subtle bug (in <a
					href="https://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcgi">kcgi</a>) in parsing the
				<code>nc</code> value when performing certain types of validation.
				An awesome set of fixes, thank you!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.9</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2019-03-24">2019-03-24</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Handle out-of-order iCal files, which is technically allowed by the
				RFC.
				This was raised by stsp@ and others on GitHub, with a patch as well!
				While there, fix handling of dates prior to 1900, which happens with
				some time zones.
				Also handle some negatively-valued recurrence values.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.1.10</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2019-11-15">2019-11-15</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				First, handle non-numeric ETag values.
				This has several steps.
				First, not parsing the values as numbers and aborting otherwise.
				Second, using randomly-generated ETag values internally instead of 
				monotonically increasing numbers.
				Third, outputting as opaque strings instead of numbers.
				This was originally reported by stsp@, thanks!
			</div>
			<div>
				Next, HTTP conditionals.
				For <code>If-Match</code>, make sure to properly handle quoted
				values as well as the <q>passthrough</q> value.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
</articles>
